Sacha Green

Insurance Professional

Tampa, FL 33617 sachab_28@yahoo.com +1 813 403 7227

Professional Summary

Professional with over 20+ years of customer support, billing, data entry, data-processing, teaching and management experience, within various industries, seeking a mid-level position in the insurance or education industry.

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

Work Experience

Licensed Insurance Professional

USAA-Tampa, FL

February 2024 to Present

- Interact with our members across multiple contact channels to provide members adequate coverage and advice to help ensure their financial security
- Facilitate the Property & Casualty member experience by handling inbound and outbound phone calls, emails, or other contacts from members
- Apply developing knowledge of personal lines' insurance to assist members with foundational to moderately complex quotes, binding new business, rating, policy, billing, payment, underwriting, contract and coverage provisions, and premium changes for insurance products and services
- Identify, evaluate and understand member needs to consistently provide complete and accurate advice and solutions for insurance products and services
- · Provide detailed issue diagnosis while minimizing member transfers, escalations and call backs
- Efficiently operate in a contact center environment and navigate multiple systems and programs while maintaining an engaging member interaction that may occur across multiple channels
- Maintain required Property & Casualty license and state registrations

Insurance Producer

Aflac-Tampa, FL June 2023 to January 2024

Licensed to insure employees with Life, Health and Annuity products.

Middle School Art Teacher

Hillsborough County Public Schools-Tampa, FL December 2021 to June 2023

Created an atmosphere which is comfortable and at the same time stimulating, thereby helping students further their knowledge of General English in the classroom.

- Designed and implements appropriate art instruction assigned in accordance with state standards, district curriculum, and students' needs.
- Created a positive educational climate for students to learn in an atmosphere of respect and rapport.
- Created and delivered relevant and rigorous art lessons that maximize student engagement and achievement.

- Observed and evaluated student performance and mastery of standards, monitored student assessment data, and maintained student grades and attendance.
- Managed student behavior in the classroom by utilizing effective classroom management strategies and invoking appropriate disciplinary procedures.
- Communicated with parents and school/district personnel regarding student progress and encouraged parental involvement.
- Took all responsible precautions to provide for the health and safety of students and to protect equipment, materials, and facilities.

English Instructor

The London Language Factory/Directors Languages-Doha, Qatar June 2021 to October 2021

Created an atmosphere which was comfortable and at the same time stimulating, thereby helping students further their knowledge of General English in the classroom.

- Planned, prepared and delivered lessons effectively, in class.
- Set tasks which challenged cadets and ensured high levels of interest.
- · Recorded and monitored attendance.
- Graded work and gave appropriate feedback.
- · Prepared military cadets for exams.

English Instructor

Ministry of Education-Dubai, AE September 2016 to August 2020

Created an atmosphere which was comfortable and at the same time stimulating, thereby helping students further their knowledge of General English in the classroom.

- Prepared and delivered lessons effectively.
- Set tasks which challenge students and ensured high levels of interest.
- · Recorded and monitored attendance.
- Graded work and gave appropriate feedback to pupils.
- Helped students improve their conversation by engaging in various English related topics.

Layout Artist

Valpak-Largo, FL

January 2005 to April 2008

Created visual designs by assembling various components.

Collected images and visual styles.

Laid out designs after approval.

Made necessary changes based on client suggestions.

Assisted other members of the team in assembling the final layout.

Administrative Assistant

Personnel One-Tampa, FL June 2003 to December 2004

Answered and directed phone calls

Organized and scheduled appointments

Planned meetings.

Wrote and distributed email, correspondence memos, letters, faxes and forms

Assisted in the preparation of regularly scheduled reports

Developed and maintained a filing system

Updated and maintained office policies and procedures
Ordered office supplies and researched new deals and suppliers
Maintained contact lists
Provided general support to visitors
Acted as the point of contact for internal and external clients

Economic Self Sufficiency Specialist

Florida Department of Children and Families-Tampa, FL November 1998 to May 2003

Answered general inquiry and complex eligibility questions related to program requirements, application processing, case status, and benefit information; follows established procedures to escalate complex case corrections to ensure resolution.

Processed a variety of eligibility related work activities including reported changes, data exchange, alerts, ASEC drivers, and case corrections including actions to supplement benefits (auxiliaries) within designated time frames as required by Federal and State laws, and Department policy and procedures. Educated customers on the benefit and features of my ACCESS Account including account set-up and password resets.

Resolved Electronic Benefit Transfer (EBT) ACCESS card issues which includes personal identification number (PIN) unlocks.

Conducted abbreviated interviews for the purpose of collecting and updating required information on applicants and recipients and their household members for all public assistance programs.

Requested all additional information/verification required to establish or continue eligibility for public assistance programs according to Department procedures.

Ensured electronic case records are documented thoroughly and properly as required by Department procedures.

Took appropriate corrective action on identified errors through the quality management system, management evaluation reviews, and quality control reviews.

Assisted customers with referrals to other agencies and community resources.

Education

Professional Development in CELTA

Teaching House - Atlanta - Atlanta, GA July 2017 to August 2017

BA in Fine Arts

University of North Florida - Jacksonville, FL June 1996 to April 1997

Associate's degree in Arts

Hillsborough Community College - Tampa, FL August 1989 to June 1992

Skills

- Team player (7 years)
- Microsoft Word (10+ years)
- Microsoft Excel (8 years)
- Microsoft PowerPoint (5 years)
- Customer support (10+ years)

- Data entry (10+ years)
- Communication skills (10+ years)
- Computer skills (10+ years)
- Interviewing (5 years)
- Insurance Sales

Languages

• English - Expert

Certifications and Licenses

Art-K12 Certificatie

November 2021 to June 2024

Life & Health Insurance License

August 2023 to Present

215 Life Incl Annuity & Health

Personal Lines License

February 2024 to Present

2-20 Licensed in all 50 states to sale Property and Casualty Insurance.